[Music]
foreign
headaches are one of the top five
reasons people end up in emergency rooms
and one of the leading reasons for which
people see their doctors in general
one of the things you can try to do to
prevent them is identify the triggers
and avoid them common triggers for
migraines include stress smoke hunger
sleep issues certain trigger foods like
chocolate cheese and alcohol your
menstrual cycle certain weather patterns
in terms of dietary treatments the
father of modern medicine William Osler
suggested trying a strict vegetable diet
after all the nerve inflammation
associated with migraines may be reduced
by a strictly plant-based diet as many
plant foods are high in
anti-inflammatory compounds and
antioxidants and likewise meat products
may have pro-inflammatory properties but
it wasn't put to the test for another
117 years
among those given a placebo supplement
half said they got better half said they
didn't but when put on a strictly
plant-based diet they did much better
experiencing a significant drop in the
severity of their pain now it's possible
that the pain reducing effects of the
plant-based diet may have at least been
in part due to the weight reduction uh
they lost about nine more pounds in
their their vegan month even just
lowering the fat content of the diet may
help those placed on a month of
consuming less than 30 grams of fat a
day like less than two tablespoons of
oil all day experience highly
significantly decreases in headache
frequency intensity duration and the
need to take medications a six-fold
decrease in frequency and intensity from
three migraine attacks every two weeks
down to just one a month and by low fat
they didn't mean snack Wells they meant
more fruits vegetables beans right
before the food industry co-opted and
corrupted the term eating low fad meant
like eating an apple not Apple Jacks
no this is a really low-fat diet like 10
fat for someone eating you know 2500
calories a day what about just less than
20 percent fat compared to a more normal
but still relatively lower fat diet than
average
same significant drops in headache
frequency and severity including a
five-fold drop in a tax of severe pain
since the intervention involved at least
you know having of saturated fat intake
mostly found in meat Dairy and junk the
researchers conclude that a reduction of
saturated fat intake may help control
migraine attacks but it's not
necessarily something they're getting
less of there are compounds present in
live green real veggies that might bind
to a migraine triggering peptide known
as cgrp drug companies have been trying
to come up with something that binds to
it but the drugs have failed to be
effective and are also toxic a problem
you don't see with cabbage green
vegetables also have magnesium found
throughout the food supply but mostly
concentrated in green leafy vegetables
beans nut seeds and whole grains it's I
say the central atom to chlorophyll so
you can see how much magnesium foods
have in the produce out by the intensity
of their green color magnesium
supplements do not appear to decrease
migraine severity but may reduce the
number of attacks you get in the first
you can ask your doctor about starting
600 milligrams of magnesium do I citrate
every day but note magnesium supplements
can cause adverse effects such as
diarrhea so I recommend getting it in
the way nature intended
any foods that may particularly help
I've talked about ground ginger uh
combining caffeine with over-the-counter
painkillers like Tylenol aspirin and
ibuprofen May boost their efficacy about
130 milligrams for tension type
headaches and 100 milligrams for
migraines about what you might expect to
get in three cups of tea though I
believe it's just a coincidence that the
principal investigator was named Lipton
no you can overdo it if you take kids
and teens who have headaches drinking
one and a half liters of cola a day and
cut the cola you can cure 90 of them
though this may be a Coca-Cola effect
rather than a caffeine effect and
finally one plant food that may not be
the best idea is this innocent looking
fellow the Carolina Reaper the hottest
chili pepper in the world so
mind-numbingly hot it can clamp off the
arteries in your brain and you can end
up with a so-called Thunderclap headache
like this 34 year old man why am I not
surprised it was a man
[Music]
foreign